[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Hello everybody. Good day, good evening
everybody. Welcome to the Ask Show. I
hope you're all doing great. Today we
are doing episode
241. And today uh we're going to discuss
my least favorite topic. We're going to
dedicate most of this ask a budget
session to the temporary nation uh by by
public demand because all the questions
have been about Pakistan and assoc
associated topics. So we're going to
discuss that. But before we do that
before I take the questions that I've
chosen from the comments, I'm going to
see who all is there on the live stream.
I can see crazy brain Akshit Ravi Prasad
chat BSP Abijit Supreme Lord Amrit Singh
Konoser of the game anti-motion clips
Bhuan Bam Mr. Jam Himmanu Sharma Vidang
Mishra Akash Ba Surendra Gupta Random
Skull Hello Martian Nisar Patel Shubhham
Toth Oscar Madison Manuk Krishna Chav
Chirai Tan Chandra Baba Ahijit Chava Duv
Hardikumar Geopolitical Dub from Indorik
Anand Chandak the medical Singh harsh
Kapoor MK Noisan Rashbir Jind Sedart
Illuminati Creek good to see you Mr.
88ers, Kuml, Action, uh, Ipsa, Tushar,
Nagar, Adita Raj, Dwari, Feminist,
Slayer, Hello GK,
Durkheiser, Gamer, Babu, Aro, Viju,
Vinit, Sanjetti, Akash, Moria, Akshit,
Vinit, Singal, Kapalin, Pushkar, Ray,
Vidi, Manar 54, Topok, Salute, uh,
Karan, Nalawad,
Jes, Anand, Anand, Chandak, Shivaray,
Djamat, Pranay, Paul from Kolkata, uh,
Nutan, Roshan, Anu, Kia Kiadi the Chad
Xenomorphosis Akshai Narval Sager G
Radhika Dvas Sumana Go and so many other
people Maklabin Tanay Chandra Chakraarti
Goautami Gamer Babu Nachika Jaman and
everybody else Gi Mishra Amisha Mishra
Bravo Williams thank you all from be for
being on the live on the live stream all
right let's take some questions where do
we begin I think yeah so we're going to
discuss our neighbor
today and and the things they do. So
what are the things they do? Let's see.
All right. What's question number one?
It's by Kish. A terrific or terrible
event happened in
Tahalgam. Deliberately key killing men
and Hindus. Was it for drama? Modi had
to short shortcut his Saudi visit and
return to India. Visas to Pakistanis
have been cancelled. People have been
called back from Pakistan. Indas and
Jalam water packs have been cancelled.
Military training and so on. PM Modi
spoke in English for a minute straight
during his speech in Bihar and he said
that we're going to chase them to the
ends of the world meaning that borders
don't matter. Okay. Pakistan is getting
geared up all during JD Vance's India
visit. Isn't this a slap at India's face
that such an event happened during such
a high-profile visit? Are we gearing up
for a war or a surgical strike? US and
China and cold war. Pakistan's army
stretch along Iran, Afghanistan,
internal issues in Baljasthan. Isn't
this the best opportunity to take back
PK like 75 different questions in one
comment? Uh thank you so much for being
a fan. I really appreciate that. So um
yeah, this terrorist attack, this
massacre happened in Pahelgam just uh
earlier this week uh and it's it's a
heinous, ghastly, barbaric, monstrous
incident that no civilized society can
tolerate. Right. and Pakistan have shown
what they're made
of. Uh so yes, this happened and then
Mr. Modi who was who was on a visit to
to the to to Saudi Arabia had to return
mid trip other cabinet ministers
wherever they were in the world whatever
trips they had to return. Um this
happened during the visit the first
visit of vice president of the US JD
Vance to India. It yeah so it's it's is
it a coincidence that it happened during
his visit? uh and there's this entire
cold war going on, the trade and tariff
war between the US and China and so much
more so much to unpack in this in this
one uh incident this absolutely horrific
unacceptable barbaric inhuman massacre
of innocent Indians, innocent Hindus,
right? So is
it is it a coincidence that this
happened during JD Vance's visit? You
know Pakistan has this uh they have this
uh habit they have this pattern that
they've exhibited of of uh linking
incidents with various events event
incident linking this happened during a
long time ago during Prime Minister
Vaj's visit to Lahore the Cargill thing
happened at the time and other things
the the parliament attack happened
during something more import something
equally important so on the Pakistanis
always linked these things so why are
they doing this so Um first of all it's
a signal it's a signal to the US that
you know we matter. The US is investing
more and more capital political capital
other capital in its relationship with
India. The relationship like I have said
a few months ago is gaining momentum.
It's going from strength to strength.
The India US relationship. It is quite
possible that the
Trumpreneur is going to see the pinnacle
of India US ties. It's it's quite
possible. Okay. So the US is investing
so much capital of various kinds in
India and uh the Pakistanis have chosen
to remind the US that you know you can
invest whatever you want in India but uh
you will need us to manage the Kashm
Kashmir thing. We can always mess
Kashmir up. It's it's it's a reminder to
the US. It's a reminder that you know we
are the managers of this this particular
corner. we can always mess it up and you
got to pay attention to us which means
you got to pay you you got to you know
um pay your dues possibly more bribes
more whatever so it's a reminder to the
US and uh it raises Pakistan's
importance in the eyes of the world uh
first of all they can claim plausible
deniability everybody was is going to
point fingers at them and then if India
does something then they can claim
victimhood it's a it's a it's an ancient
it's a very old tried and true tactic
isn't it. So there is that uh that's
that's another thing that the Pakistanis
have most likely wanted to do to to
bring uh the eyes of the world on on on
this thing. So uh this is uh so and and
the other thing they want to do is to
internationalize the Kashmir matter.
There is no Kashmir issue. You know
there is no Kashmir issue in the world.
The issue that we have in the world is a
Pakistan issue. The issue is Pakistan.
The issue is not Kashmir. But Pakistan
wants to keep on harping about the
Kashmir issue and they want to ind
internationalize this matter by forcing
Kashmir back onto the front page
headlines in the world and and forcing
Kashmir onto the front page of Donald
Trump's uh daily uh intelligence
briefing that he gets you know top top
secret intelligence briefing that he
gets a dosier he gets every morning.
Kashmir is going to figure on that now.
So they want to dilute India's claim
that the dispute is that this matter is
settled. India is saying that Kashmir is
is a settled matter. Uh there's no
dispute and they they want to raise this
you know. Uh so that's the thing. Now
the Indust Valley Industry has been
abrogated or or
whatever put into obeyance whatever
technology whatever technical term you
want to use about that but that's what's
happened right. Uh now the real question
is uh does any evidence
point to a third
power right? Uh is it only Pakistan? Is
there somebody behind Pakistan? Uh what
what's the question? Are we gearing up
for a war or a surgical tri strike? US,
China, Baloistan. Yeah. All of this is
interconnected. We don't quite have any
evidence that any other power may be
involved in this matter. But yeah,
uh what are the other questions? PM Modi
has said that we're going to chase them
to the ends of the world. Yeah, good. Uh
the all of the world's leaders, major
leaders have uh unequivocally voiced
their support to to India. Uh uh the US
has done that, President Trump of the US
did that. Uh various other world leaders
did that. Even the foreign minister of
Iran did that. Interesting. The Taliban
has um has uh voiced support has
expressed support towards India. Uh the
the director of the national
intelligence of the U Miss Gabbard even
said that Hindus were targeted. She
herself is a Hindu which helps and so
on. Uh yes. So uh this is kind of an
inflection point. U things will never be
the same for Pakistan again. I can
assure you of that. something has
changed in the world order that Pakistan
doesn't seem to have realized and uh
whether they have walked wittingly or
unwittingly into this thing. Uh things
are never going to be the same for
Pakistan. Their star is now on the
decline. Now what happens going forward
is is going to remain in the hands of
Prime Minister Modi. Mr. Modi gets to
decide what happens next as the as the
leader of of of uh the nation of India
and I am not privy to what what could
happen. Um all the cards are on the
table. We could uh take there are lots
of there are various measures that we
have uh at our disposal.
Um we can we obviously have the Indus
waters leverage now the the three rivers
that were given away to Pakistan we can
start leveraging the water there in a
variety of ways uh we can strangulate
Pakistan slowly drop by drop we can do
that and there's the option of surgical
strikes there's the option of a of
a pulse pause war a brief short sharp
war there this there's many options that
we have. Um, yeah. So, this is what's
happened. What are the other questions
you've asked over here? We're going to
take lots of questions about this. Uh,
is this a slap at India's face? It's
it's a stupid thing to do. You know, it
doesn't hurt. I know 26 people died.
These are each death is a tragedy in its
own. It's it's a tragedy for each family
and every every loved one who who these
dead people leave behind. It's it's a
horrific tragedy. Yes. So that that that
stands indeed. But overall as a nation
we are 1.4 billion people. Does this
hurt
us?
They maybe they they wish to hurt us in
certain ways. Maybe they want to portray
India as a nation that uh is is not a
safe destination for uh for investment
and so on. But it doesn't really work
that way. Uh so I think it's it's a
disastrously stupid move by Pakistan and
it's going to haunt them for the rest of
their existence however long or short it
may be because Pakistan is an artificial
temporary nation and the temporary
status just got heightened now. It's
gone up several notches for
sure. Pray Paul always asks great
questions. In the current volatile
geopolitical backdrop, is there any
doubt left that the Pakistan army
orchestrated this attack? Why strike now
right when the US vice president is
visiting India? Coincidence or
deliberate signaling? Is the objective
only to dispute disrupt Kashmir's rise
or could there be the involvement of
foreign power with any clear indicators
given the Pakistan army's deep
understanding of the likely
repercussions? What could be the drive
what could be driving them to risk such
escalation? Is this part of a bigger
trap to provoke India into rushing into
a quick uh military reaction? Um and do
you believe that such a smooth
coordinated attack could happen without
some form of local support? These are
very interesting questions. So first of
all let's take the question of whether
uh it's the Pakistan army that
orchestrated this attack or maybe like
they say it is a homegrown thing or
whatever. Look if you look at the
operational fingerprints of what
happened they point in one direction
unmistak unmistakably towards Rahal
Pindi Pakistan.
the Pakistanis will keep on denying it.
Okay. Uh some new organization, terror
organization, TRA for something uh seems
to have taken credit for what happened.
Look, this whatever this organization
is, it's not some kind of local
autonomous terrorist cell or whatever.
It is a disposable alias of of leashar a
whatever that thing is, right? and
Lashkar a whatever le is an extension of
the
ISI. Okay. And these various disposable
aliases that these people use a new
organization exists for 3 months here
and 3 months there and 6 months here and
6 months there. These are used you know
that's a very old tactic they they
they've been using in the 1990s there
was something called Ansar or something.
Every every time they come up with a new
name which is nothing but a disposable
alias. It's a disposable mask that the
LT wears and the LED itself is a mask of
the ISI. Okay. So, uh it's clear uh and
and then and the ISI they you uses these
disposable masks to launder these terror
attacks and and
and claim that they are indigenous.
Okay. But we know that there's there's I
mean you know Indian intelligence, US
intelligence, everyone knows that
there's clear connections of funding
networks that connect the ISI with the L
with all these all these various the all
these organizations u there are various
so-called charities in Lahore and
whatnot that that do the the dirty work
the funding the the funneling of money
and whatnot and so on you know so um
there's no question that uh all the
operational u fingerprints point in the
direction of the
ISI. Now like I said some time ago by
the the what's the objective? They want
to internationalize the Kashmir matter.
They want to claim that Kashmir is not
settled. It is still a dispute and so
on. And no matter what India does by
abrogating article 370, by ending
article 370 and normalizing the
situation, it still doesn't matter.
Pakashir is still a dispute. They want
to internationalize the matter. That's
number one. Secondly, they want to send
a message to Washington like I said that
you know Pakistan matters and Pakistan
is is the entity that will uh manage
this this region and no matter how much
you invest in India there's always going
to be a liability in Kashmir and
Pakistan is needed to manage it uh that
sort of thing.
Um so that's the kind of message they
are sending to the world to the US and
so on. Now the question once again
that's being asked is whether there is
any uh external factor is there any
outside hand in this is there a third
power fourth power perhaps involved in
this so look uh there's no conclusive
evidence that we have that any other
power is involved beyond
Pakistan conclusive evidence doesn't
exist but where does the incentive lie
you know the incentive structure it
aligns it doesn't align with the US
geopolitical interest. I'll tell you
that. Okay. The incentive for for what
happened here, it aligns very neatly
with Beijing Beijing's interests. So at
at the time that this terror attack
happened, there was a there was a
concurrent at the same time there was a
a military exercise that was going on in
Pakistan occupied Kashmir with with the
involvement of Pakistani forces and
Chinese forces. Okay. Military
exercise and uh and we know that
Pakistan we know that China is facing
the US pressure and India and the US are
cooperating in the field of
semiconductors and whatn not and this
was recently announced during JD Vance's
trip to to India right so so it it
really helps uh China if if things don't
keep going wrong in India this this
terror attacks and what not so the
incentive is there but there is no clear
evidence
and u and let's say there are tensions
in the Kashmir region there's a flare up
of violence maybe there's a uh there are
surgical strikes maybe there is a short
sharp war or whatever so if that happens
you're going to have all the a large
number of Indian forces pinned to the
western front of India right you if in
in in case that happens that indirectly
eases pressure on the LAC line of actual
control where you have a huge buildup of
armed forces on both sides India and
China in recent times past year or so
India and China have been slowly
bringing the tension down the tensions
down but if China feel that you know
India is aligning with the US and it's
there's no point uh uh being nice with
India then they could do such things uh
so if so if there's a flare up on the
western border of on India's western
border then it it it eases the pressure
on the LAC with Tibet the line of actual
control with with Tibet and there there
are connections between China and
Pakistan
you know um there is this
uh they have been constructing fiber
optic links fiber links between Pakistan
occupied Kashmir and Singinjang part of
China. So you can see that there are
cross connections between the the the
the PLA and the
ISI. So there are these circumstantial
pieces of evidence but there is no clear
uh unambiguous evidence that points in a
third powers direction. Right now the
question that's also been being asked is
why does Pakistan do such things? Why
what what is it that drives Pakistan to
risk this sort of explanation to this
sort of escalation? Right? So look there
are domestic factors first of all the
Pakistani economy is is constantly
collapsing. Uh the IMF bailout is still
is is is not happening. It's it is under
negotiation and uh there are civilian
protests that happen. There's the
Balojasthan issue. um the army's
domestic aura has been eroded so they
need some kind of external factor to to
get the people to rally around the army
again right makes sense right and and
and the Pakistan army it obviously
calculates that their nuclear shield
gives them uh protection against India
and it will also this nuclear shield and
the nuclear matter will also ensure that
you know great powers like the US will
immediately step in and mediate and
prevent India from taking things beyond
a surgical level or a symbolic level
like Bala court etc. Yeah. Um and by
demonstrating that uh that Pakistan by
demonstrating that they can you know
disrupt tourism and destabilize Kashmir
at will uh they probably want to get
some concessions from India. Uh but
they've done the opposite. Indust treaty
is gone and so on. Now what uh Prrenai
asks is that is is this
uh is this a trap? Is this part of a
bigger trap to provoke India into
something stupid? Yeah, it could be. It
could be uh India will have
to calibrate and calculate whatever
response it
takes. Some some response will happen.
Some response has already happened.
We've
expelled a significant amount of number
of uh Pakistani diplomats or military
attaches or whatever and we've brought
our our people back as well from our
embassy there and the industry has been
abrogated whatever put in obeyance etc.
But there could be more coming up. There
could be more coming up. You know, if
India doesn't plan things properly and
just gets angry and and acts in
anger, you know, doesn't incursion a
ground incursion of Pakistan or maybe
tries to take Poke back, then it will
give Pakistan grounds to to to play the
victim, you know, uh and and that then
they will obviously give this will also
give China the opportunity to to give
diplomatic shielding to Pakistan. So it
so Pakistan gets to posture as a as a
besieged victim you know um so India is
going to have to calculate things
properly and and do do it the right way.
Now the last question that PR asks is
that could this have happened without
local support? Yeah, could this have
happened without local support? Pakistan
I don't think I have to show anyone the
map in in this matter. We know we all
know the map between India and Pakistan
the border region. Pakistan is a long
border with
India. Most of it is not disputed or or
or or you know held Indian territory not
held by Pakistan most of it. Right. We
have a long border in Rajasthan. We
we've got a long border in Gujarat. Yes.
So how come there's no terrorism in
Rajasthan or
Gujarat? Because there's no local
support. People will say there's desert
and all that. These, you know, these
people live in
deserts. They can deal with deserts.
Okay? These are desert people. Um
there's no local support in Rajasthan or
Gujarat. Look what happened in
Pahelam. This massacre it to to make it
happen. You know what the terrorists
needed? They needed advanced
reconnaissance of the flow of tourists,
tourists flows. They needed to have a
clear dayby-day granular
understanding of tourist flows. What
day, how many tourists come? When did
the tourism start, tourist season start,
where do they come from? Which which uh
operators bring tourists to what spots?
What if if someday the weather is bad,
what happens? And so on so forth. So you
need advanced reconnaissance of tourist
flows. You need covert safe houses in
the area around Pahelgam and you need u
the facility of extent of instantaneous
exfiltration immediately get the get the
terrorists out so that they cannot be
captured. So you need granular
situational awareness and this is not
possible without what they call OGWs.
What's an OGW? It's an overground
worker. You see
in in this field of terrorism or
whatever you want to call it there are
two kinds of
operators. There is overground workers
and there is underground workers.
Underground workers are the guys who are
hidden and they come out only with the
AK-47s or whatever. Okay. Who are the
overground workers? The overground
workers are your local transportation
people. They are your hotel people.
Hello sir, is everything fine today sir?
Do you need something sir? The hotel
folks. So you have people who work in
hotels, people who uh let's say the
hotel
networks uh you have transport unions,
you have your taxi drivers,
uh you the tour operator network, all
that stuff. This is you if you are a
terrorist and you want to you know uh
target tourists who come into Kashmir
you need overground workers in these
networks. Okay.
So it's a given that this was there and
you know after the pelgam attack
happened uh our security agencies have
already rounded up more than a dozen
such uh facilitators or overground
workers uh who have been you know uh
playing this role. So there is this uh
infiltration of of the overground uh you
know of all these of of all these uh
networks by the
ISIL you know combination and that's how
they have been so successful in Kashmir.
So you know uh Kashmir uh after the the
removal of article 370 I mean what has
changed in Kashmir after that? Yeah
tourism has started booming again. This
is what happens when you go and spend
your money in Kashmir. This is what you
get in in recompense for that. Yeah. You
think everything has changed? Things
don't change until you change things at
a very fundamental level. You to start
with changing the education system and
the schooling system and all that. But
that the government will not do. Right?
Societies change
slowly. Just because something a few
cosmetic changes were done doesn't mean
the whole society will change. They are
the same people.
to change society you have to change it
at a very fundamental level which is why
I keep harping on about the education
system and other
things. So um that's not happened and
Kashmir the population of Kashmir is the
same right. So this is what you get
uh by by giving them tourism
revenue. So look uh bottom line this is
an ISIR operation very calibrated ISI
operation. It is timed to to coincide
with uh the strategic momentum in India
US ties. It is time to coincide with the
visit of JD vans to India. It is testing
it is it is a test it is designed to
test India. It is designed to test
India's escalation discipline and so on.
Um and India's response must
punish the perpetrators without giving
Pakistan the international limelight
they want. Understand that. So that's
what India has to do. And there are lots
of ways of strangulating Pakistan. Gray
zone strangulation, economic
strangulation, water strangulation, so
much that India can leverage. India is
going to have to do it judiciously,
carefully.
uh the international opinion is with
India. There's no question about that.
Uh so use that judiciously and let's
start the clock ticking on the temporary
nation. This is the inflection
point. This is no longer the same India
that we had in 2019 where did they did
whatever else. This is a different India
and this time Pakistan must be made to
pay. Okay. Poor the planet says the
recent pahelgam attack in Kashmir seems
far from random. It can be a calculated
move by China executed through Pakistan
to destabilize India at a critical time.
With the US imposing heavy tariffs on
Chinese goods, many global companies
have started shifting their supply
chains to India threatening China's
economic dominance. To counter this
shift, China could be using its close
ally Pakistan to create international
unrest, internal unrest in India,
especially in sensitive regions like
Kashmir. By doing so, China may China's
goal may be to project India as unstable
and unsafe for foreign investment,
thereby slowing its rising momentum as a
global manufacturing hub. This isn't
just terrorism. It's economic warfare
design disguised as a regional conflict.
Now this is a really um international
interesting um point that you raise
here. Uh what's the deal? So
look like it's so it's clear that look
China does benefit if if things go wrong
in
Kashmir. China um right now what's
happening is that the world is seeking
alternatives to China. You have marqu uh
manufacturers like Apple who are
increasingly shifting production to
India. You know I don't care what the
media says it's happening more and more
of the production that was happening in
China is now being moved to India and
China needs China it's great for China
if India is gets portrayed as an unsafe
destination right now. What is it that
takes
uh if you if you are a foreign
manufacturer and if you're wondering
whether you should come to India and
manufacture India, what does it take to
convince you? First of all, you know,
the business environment should be good.
The government should give you good
treatment. You should get all the
facilities you need. You need to have a
good stable labor force uh and so on.
All that is there in India. Mostly it's
there in India. The thing the things
that keep people away make them wonder
whether they should not come is if you
have constant terrorism and you know
unsafe environment and if if it's very
hard to have uh contracts enforced and
things like that. So
uh the uh manufacturing that Apple is
doing is happening in southern India if
I'm not mistaken and what happens in
Kashmir is kind of usually by by if you
if you're a foreign investor you don't
connect what's happening in Kashmir to
what's happening in the rest of India
because everyone knows that Kashmir is
right next to the terror terror factory
that's Pakistan and Kashmir has
historically been targeted by Pakistan.
So if if there are terror attacks that's
happening in other parts of India that's
a red flag. If it's happening in Kashmir
then then foreign investors don't really
uh uh get uh don't see it as a red flag.
Okay. Now understand this u so if India
is projected as an unsafe destination it
helps China for sure. So there is
definitely strategic convergence of
interests here. But understand it's not
a hierarchical convergence. It's a
strategic uh convergence. It's it's it's
just the Yeah. So it's not
hierarchical. The whatever has happened
has been probably done by the ISI and
the LE and
whatnot. Beijing does benefit from this
but I don't think there is any clear
sign that they are involved. they can
they will definitely give u their
diplomatic backing to Pakistan the their
diplomatic shielding to Pakistan but you
know Beijing one thing if you look at
their track record you will understand
they do not outsource sectarian
terrorism see how does Beijing generally
like to operate Beijing is a bully we
know that right Beijing is a bully how
do they operate visav their neighbors
except for Russia all other nations are
are smaller than them, right? So they
are the big bully in the region except
for when it comes to the relationship
with Russia. How do they do they treat
their other neighbors? First of all,
they indulge in salami slicing, slicing
away territory. Every single neighbor
neighboring country, they do this to
them. They have been doing this to
everyone and we we know it very very
well. They've deliberately not they've
deliberately not uh demarcated the
border. they choose to keep the border
issue open India Tibet border so that
they can keep salami slicing wherever
the opportunity may or may not present
itself right so one thing they do is
salami slicing the other thing they do
is various other kinds of bullying you
know whether it is the South China Sea
kind of thing island building or
whatever that's sort of bullying they do
and uh the one thing they don't do is
outsource sectarian terrorism because
that tarnishes their image and they they
have been at pains to to present a
spotless image to the world
diplomatically, internationally, etc.
that we we uh have an unimpeach an un
unimpeachable track record and uh our
rise is a peaceful rise and so
on. And if they were to indulge in
things like these, you know, get
involved in Pakistani terrorism against
India, it can come back to bite them
because they they have a significant
investment in in Central Asia, even
Pakistan, the belt and road initiative.
the in Pakistan it's called the CPEC the
China Pakistan economic corridor and
they have been facing um um attacks
along that corridor from Balojasthan
freedom fighters and and others and if
they start funding Pakistani terrorism
or getting involved in that directly
then it can come back to bite them very
badly so I don't think China will be
directly involved in this they certainly
their their interests will certainly be
served by what happened but u I think uh
their their presence or or their
participation in this could be in in
limited to giving diplomatic backing and
diplomatic shielding to Pakistan once
this goes to the UN and other things.
Beyond that, I don't think uh China will
directly get involved in this and there
is no evidence of that
whatsoever.
Okay. Okay. This is an important
question. Kish and Brianka Shikhar
Biswas did they just admit it? We have
been doing this dirty work for the US
and the west for three decades. Did
Pakistan just admit that they backed
terrorism for the US and UK? What
happens now? Miganga says what are the
broad broader implications of the
Pakistan's defense min of Pakistan's
defense minister admitting on live
interview with sky
news that Pakistan has been carrying out
the dirty work for western powers like
the US and the UK in the Indian
subcontinent pres particularly in the
con context of regional stability
sovereignty balance of power etc. What
he admitted is that Pakistan is a proxy
for the west in carrying out terror
attack against India and we have been
doing this dirty word work for more than
three decades. That's what he
said. Viewers of the Ask a Bajit show
will know I have
been saying this for a very long time
that the US funded and financed
Pakistani terrorism in India for
decades. Right? It it they started in
essentially and I was saying this when
it was not fashionable to say it. Today
the Pakistani defense minister
corroborates what I have been saying.
Everyone knew this. Everyone in who
knows things knew it but nobody would
say it. Well now the defense minister of
Pakistan say it on this live interview.
It's there. You can see the clip anytime
you want. it will never go away from
social
media. Right? So he said
this. So
this
is so why did he say it first of all is
the question. Right? Why why why did he
uh make this
admission? Why did you make the
admission that Pakistan has been
uh uh
so so look first of all we know that
since the 1980s the west has treated
Pakistan's support for terrorism as an
open secret
okay if if if you know how things work
you will know that it it's been an open
secret especially uh at higher levels
that everyone knew that Pakistan is a is
a proxy for the US and the UK and the
west and in the 19 this all happened
because in the cold war India was not in
the side of the west not on the side of
the west India was on the side of the
USSR and that's why India had to be
contained and India had to be put in its
place and one of the ways to do it is by
using Pakistan as a terror factory and
terrorize India starts with Punjab then
in Kashmir right and then rest of India
also terror attacks all all over the
place so the US funded finance
this now um the west
ignored this. They publicly ignored
this. Privately they knew it but they
publicly ignored this. As long as
Islamabad
uh gave those statements you know those
those platitudes counterterror
platitudes oh we believe we are against
terrorism and we are doing this zerbe a
or some some god knows what operation
they had done at some point in time and
so on. uh all that. So this guy uh Huaja
Af I think his name is he said this on
camera we have been doing this dirty
work this takes the mass off the mask
off this thing you know so um there's
the end this is the end of deniability
Pakistan can no longer deny the west can
no longer deny what's been happening
okay so Pakistan's legitimacy is gone
Pakistan you know what they used to
claim they used to claim that they were
the leaders of the Islamic world against
unjust imperialist designs of the
west. Now it turns out that according to
their own defense minister Pakistan has
been operating for decades as an
imperialist as an imperial
subcontractor as a mercenary for the
imperialists. So their standing is gone
now. Okay, their standing is gone in in
the Islamic world in whatever world they
were positioning themselves.
And when it comes to when it comes to
the US, when it comes to Washington,
when it comes to London, they now have
to make a decision. They have to choose
between
uh whether they want to um see they will
have to either distance themselves from
Pakistan, which will now make Pakistan
once again go into the arms of
China, or they will have to own up to
what they've done and give Pakistan some
kind of uh security or something.
Um so that that's kind of where we are.
So this guy has slipped up perhaps uh
deliberately perhaps not. Maybe there's
an election coming up and he wants to
you know whatever is going wrong in
Pakistan. Blame it on the west blame it
on the masters. Maybe it's a sign that
the west has ditched Pakistan and
Pakistan is looking for a new master.
Please understand this. Okay. Maybe it
is a sign of that. I'm I'm telling you
from the beginning of this episode,
right? Something has changed in the
world. you can sense it at at a certain
level. So something has changed
somewhere and this statement by the
Pakistan defense minister perhaps is a
is a very strong indication that
something has changed and Pakistan is
seeking a new master now and and if you
want a new master you have to disown the
past master. So the best way to do it is
to say it on live
TV, you know, and and put all the blame
on them for everything that went wrong.
So I think now Pakistan China
convergence could happen. Um and this is
going to be difficult for Pakistan. They
will have to now rely on Beijing in if
that is the case for aid for their
handouts because the IMF, the World
Bank, things will be difficult for them.
Uh so
look it's an open it's always been an
open secret for people in the no not for
the common people but it's always been
an open secret for people who who
understood how things worked in the
world.
Uh so Pakistan has been exposed they
they have confessed that they they are a
mercenary state. They've been doing this
dirty work and uh yeah so that's where
we are.
uh sovereignty the question the question
Brianka raises is that of sovereignty
stability etc balance of power it's all
fine balance of power it'll change
somewhat if the west has decided to
ditch Pakistan which seems to be the
case uh then yes China Pakistan
convergence happens which means the
India India China they don't rapo etc
where does it go is the question are we
going to see more flareups on the lac
now we have to be you know we're going
to have to keep these things in mind.
But when it comes to
sovereignty, Pakistan is a mercenary
state. Mercenary state, it's a contract.
It's a contractor. It's it's a terrorism
contractor, security subcontractor,
whatever you want to say. It's not a
sovereign state. It's never been a
sovereign state. Okay? And the Pakistan
army doesn't defend national
honor. The Pakistan army works for
whoever pays them the
most. Okay? So all of that is is now
completely exposed and I'm I'm telling
you something this is an inflection
point. Whatever the the events that
happened this week uh they represent an
inflection point in the history of
Pakistan. It's the clock is now ticking
on Pakistan. I don't know how long it
will take whether it's it is 3 months or
3 years or 15 years but it's ticking now
and it's a countdown that's begun. Okay.
It's not ticking forward it's ticking
backwards.
It's a countdown. It'll it'll it's it's
counting down to zero now for
Pakistan. Okay. Pranay says, "Could you
explain what exactly the Indust treaty
is and why it's been so crucial to
Pakistan's survival all these years? How
did previous Indian governments allow a
situation where nearly 80% of the river
waters were given away to Pakistan while
India was left with only 20 about 20%
Isn't it high time we fix these historic
blunders? With India now moving to scrap
or fundamentally alter the treaty. What
could be the long-term implications for
Pakistan's agricultural economy,
internal stability? Do you see this is a
far more devastating and permanent tool
of pressure compared to short-term
military actions? That's a great
question. Look, look, my friends,
listen. Pay
attention. A missile strike hurts,
right? A missile strike hurts. It causes
pain. It causes
damage. The damage happens
once. Boom. Right? Let's say you send 20
missiles. Let's say you say send a 100
missiles. It's going to cause a certain
quantum of damage and pain. And then
time erases
that. You squeeze
water slowly, gradually, drip by drip,
drop by drop, 1%, 2%, 3%, 7%,
10%.
That is not visible. There is no damage
that's visible. There's no pain that's
visible, but it is an incredible squeeze
or a nation that depends on the up river
waters.
That is a far
greater pressure point, leverage point,
pain point, whatever you want to call
it, than missile strikes in military
action. You can bring a nation to its
knees by doing
this. So now with that said, what's the
industry? It is a treaty that was signed
sometime in 1960, I believe, under the
opices of the World Bank.
uh and at that time our our prime
minister was Mr. Nehu, Mr. Javaharal
Nehu. So uh we have six rivers in the
STAindu region which is strange because
it's STAU seven rivers but there are six
rivers in there because one river left
it left the Sarasati left so we have six
rivers in this region the Sapasindu
region uh in Punjab Panchaba yeah that
sort of thing right so we have two
nations one temporary one permanent and
we have six rivers so in 1960 this
treaty was uh signed between India
Pakistan the World Bank engineered this
treaty. Mr. Nehu accepted it. Uh so
India got exclusive or near exclusive
use of three smaller rivers the eastern
rivers the Ravi the bayas and the
satlajush and Pakistan was given
complete
unrestricted water of the three western
rivers the indust the sindu river the
jalam and the chinab and India is given
the the right to tap into the western
rivers for non-conumptive purposes if if
you want to use it for hydro,
electricity or flood control or whatever
that sort of thing and and if you do
that you have to share all the technical
data with the Pakistanis in advance so
that they know exactly what's happening
and um and then there are dispute
resolving mechanisms and and whatnot and
this treaty has no expiry date and it
has survived
uh how many wars I don't know one 65 71
uh what else the the cargle war the
three wars so it survived three wars and
the treaty has never has stood until now
but now India has ended it. India
suspended the treaty.
Uh so that's the Indust treaty. It gave
80% of the waters
uh of of of the indust of of of these
rivers to Pakistan comp. It must be the
most lopsided one-sided treaty in the
history of human of of of humanity. Not
even a defeated power accepts a treaty
like this. such a one-sided
treaty. So yes and you know I have a
video on this channel about the Indust
treaty about from 22 2022 or 23 I think
about a couple of years ago in which
I've spoken about this and the steps
India has been taking and I've been
saying that India needs to uh revisit
this treaty and you know fix this
historic
blunder. So the Pakistanis by doing the
Pulwama the Pahelgam massacre have well
finally it's I think it's the straw that
broke the camel's back and that's it.
It's the end of an
era. Um so what are the going to be the
long-term implications of Pakistan's
agriculture economy internal stability?
Now India is going to control what
happens. We may not have complete access
to complete control over all the waters
because the western rivers uh they they
uh flow in the Himalayas and the
mountains and it's very hard to dam them
but we have various run of the run of
the river projects and all that's going
on. It's going to give us enough control
to you know to ramp up the amount of
water we can retain in India and divert
elsewhere.
And many of these projects that we are
undertaking, they will come to fruition
in the next five, six, seven years
maximum. So you're going to see
increasing pressure on Pakistan.
Increasing amounts of water will be
diverted by India now. And there's
nothing the Pakistanis can do about
this. They can go to court,
international court, blah blah blah. Do
whatever you want. I don't care anymore.
Yes, of course. You know some people
will say and they are right to say this
that it gives the China the historical
precedent for doing something similar to
us because they control some of our up
river upstream uh you know some of the
upstream regions of our rivers like the
brahaputra the Ganga
etc. um especially the brahmaputra is
important but you know it's okay we
we'll deal with it if if it comes to
that and when it comes to the
brahmaputra 80% of the waters of the
brahmaputra the the the river gets you
know gets those waters from within India
itself from Arunachal and other places
only 20% comes from Tibet so it's not
going to be a huge issue we can we'll
have to find ways to deal with that if
the if the Chinese take if the Chinese
go down that that road uh But Pakistan
Pakistan is going to face serious
trouble now because it's its agriculture
is dependent on this water. Most of its
agriculture is dependent on the water
that comes from these three rivers and
it's it's a very poor country. It's
dependent on agriculture. I don't know
how much of its GDP comes from
agriculture but at least about 30 40% of
its workforce is employed in the
agriculture sector. And uh yeah it it
could be really bad times for Pakistan.
and and they deserve it. I mean, how
long can a nation like India just keep
enduring this nonsense, terrorism?
There's going to be a time when we're
going to give it back. So, I think more
than a war, this could be the the thing
that squeezes Pakistan and really brings
it to its
knees. Okay. The Rajat Dalal says
India's ability to restrict water to
Pakistan is constrained by natural
hydraological cycles, infrastructure
gaps and treaty design rules. The vast
majority of the India systems water will
continue to flow to Pakistan due to
natural natural geography and treaty
limitations but with seasonal
variations. Almost all Indians do not
understand and they believe that IWT
suspension has stopped the water from
going to Pakistan. What's my opinion on
the IWT suspension? Naval blockade from
southern Pakistan and building dam on
indis are two solid options that I see.
Mr. 88 says that India suspended the IWT
in Indis water treaty. What's the
essence of suspending the treaty since
we have no storage dams on the on the
western rivers and building dams? It
takes time. It'll take at least 10
years. So how will this affect Pakistan?
Right? So the question is why suspend a
treaty when there are no big dams on
these rivers? These big dams don't exist
yet. So please understand one thing.
This is not a plumbing switch that you
know we're going to switch switch it off
and the water water dries out. It's not
that. It's not a plumbing switch. This
is a legal this is a legal switch. The
legal offramp. So the suspension.
So first of all you have to understand
that no nation is is required to keep on
abiding to a treaty that is not in its
favor or that that that severely
uh is is is is loaded against it. There
are so many historical precedents of
nations walking away unilaterally from a
treaty. Donald Trump walked away from
the Iran nuclear deal. The JWST uh JW uh
forget I I
JCPOA joint comprehensive plan of
action. not the JWS, James Webb, what am
I doing? So, Donald Trump walked away
from it from the Iran nuclear deal
unilaterally despite the treaty being
signed according to international law.
The Chinese had an agreement, a treaty
with with the UK about about uh Hong
Kong, the status of Hong Kong, one
nation, two systems. They walked away
from it. They said, "We no longer
recognize that unilaterally." So if a
treaty victimizes you or or you know if
it is unfair to you, you have the right
to walk away from it. So India is
walking away from the treaty. That's it.
There are there is historical precedent
for that. That's number one. Please
understand that. So now once you say
publicly and and you announce that you
are walking away from a treaty, the
treaty is suspended or whatever
technical term you want you want to use,
then you can start doing things, taking
actions. As long as the treaty in is in
force, you're not allowed to build dams,
right? You're not allowed to build dams.
So the suspension of the treaty has
removed India's own self-binding
obligations. Okay? All those things uh
you know disclose in advance whatever
whatever plans you have and you need
neutral experts to arbitrate everything
and how much water you can store in in
in in of the western rivers. there's a
there's a cap to it beyond which India
cannot cannot store more water and so
on. So from now on from this point on
India can approve projects without
having to wait for Pakistani objections
or anything or World Bank mediation. No
more need to worry about Pakistani
objections or World Bank mediation. So
what you have had for the 60 for the
past 64 years is that the Pakistanis had
an
entitlement. They were entitled to the
Indust. Now India has turned it into a
revocable privilege. If we choose then
you can have it. If we don't if we
choose not to give it to you then you
don't get it. We decide. So now it's a
privilege. It's not no longer an
entitlement for Pakistan. Now what
leverage does India have? We have no
huge dams right? We have something
called runoff river projects. So we
don't have storage dams but uh we are
operating multiple uh projects we are
and we are currently building and in the
process of finishing about a dozen run
of the river projects uh hydropower
plants like Kushin Ganga like Dul Hasti
like Ratlay like Pakal pal Dul uh Sabal
Court and so on so forth okay I don't
remember so all the names these
run-of-the- river schemes have ponds
attached to them which is like a daily
or weekly balancing pond. So if you
coordinate the gate operations of all
these of multiple runoff the river
projects reservoirs in tandem at the
same time you can pause you can withhold
very large quantities of water you can
do that during Pakistan's agricultural
season so that will that will cause
havoc downstream and you can do this
actually without violating any
international humanitarian norms or
whatever. So and and if you want to do
fast track fast track storage of water,
it's no longer going to take India 10
years to do that. So there are multiple
uh western river projects that are
currently under construction like the
ones I named and most of these see one
of them I think it is Takalul it it
becomes operational next year I think
and there is Ratlay that becomes
operational in 2028 and Sabal court in
29 and these will add a huge capacity of
lives of live storage of water and and
there is uh there are other projects
that are going to become operational in
the in the early
2030s. So in the next 7 8 years we're
going to have storage capacity of
several
billion cubic meters of water in the
region. So do you understand it's not
just talk anymore. It's not just talk
anymore. We actually can squeeze the
Pakistanis without crossing the what
they call the kinetic threshold. You see
you can do air strikes which is like you
do it once and then the world says stop
and you have to stop it. Aer strikes you
do it once and stop. Water leverage is
continuous. It is immune to diplomatic
pressure and diplomatic vetos. It is
invisible.
Okay. So uh that's that's huge. And and
we can we can you know throttle the flow
of water incrementally.
So it gives us gives us a graduated
response ladder that will short that
will stop short of humanitarian
catastrophe but it keeps Pakistan under
constant
pressure and you can apply it at will.
You understand? So it's not about
turning off the tap tomorrow morning. it
this this suspension of the industry has
unlocked a huge toolkit that is going to
grow more painful for Pakistan every
agricultural season even before the
first mega dam is finished.
So this is slow burn leverage that we
have and it's it's going to be
compounded by financial and diplomatic
costs that India can impose on Pakistan.
So we can achieve what military actions
sporadic military actions whether it is
air strikes like Bala code or it is the
surgical strikes that that is just
symbolic. This leverage that we now get
is going to force behavioral change on
Pakistan. Painful behavioral change on
Pakistan while we keep our growth
trajectory intact. Do you understand?
That's the implication of the abrogation
suspension abing whatever it is of the
industry. It's huge. It's it's genuine
leverage we get. This is an inflection
point in the history of Pakistan.
Whatever amount of time it is the
Pakistanis have left for the country.
This is where it changes. This is where
it all all
changes. Pran Paul says, "Considering
Trump's track record of channeling arms
and aid to Pakistan, Israel and Egypt,
how likely is it that the US would adopt
a double-faced stance if a full-scale
IndiaPakistan war breaks out? Could
Washington again under the garb of
restraint try to diplomatically pressure
India especially amid global economic
fragility and shaping uh shifting
alliances? Is there a real danger that
the US would once again prop up Pakistan
either directly or indirectly? Or are
they now merely in it to sell weapons to
both sides and profit of instability
despite Pakistan's strategic irrelevance
and internal collapse? Do you foresee
any surprise alignments forming around
it? How might how might China exploit
the situation? Would it remain
calculatedly neutral or would it seize
the chaos to challenge India on a second
front?
Look, okay, let's consider the scenarios
you are uh uh painting for us. It's a
good exercise in in the thought
experiment. So, let's say Washington
wants to sell weapons to both sides.
Let's say India and Pakistan go to war.
H and Washington says, "Oh yeah, let's
let's uh grab the opportunity to sell
weapons to both sides." What money does
Pakistan have? Do they have the capacity
to absorb US weapons? Do they have money
to pay the Americans? They are going to
the World Bank and the IMF with begging
balls,
right? Where's the
money? What's the point of selling
anything to Pakistan? And what what does
the US get out of it? The US at this
point at this juncture in
history finds itself in a situation
where they have to invest in
India invest political capital invest
technological capital other other and
other kinds of capital in India because
of the situation with
China we have reached a bigger
inflection point a couple of weeks ago
when the tariff war started the US
imposed 145% tariffs on on China the
Chinese retaliated by 125% tariffs
tariffs which means the system is gone.
There's no more trade between between
the US and China. Supply chains are
fragmenting. The world is
bifurcating and the US needs India on
its
side. It's part of the of the of the
broader Indopacific
strategy. They need nations like India
on its side, Australia, Japan who are
its vasals anyway etc. But India is is a
major lynchpin in the strategy. And if
India goes on the on the other side,
then it's a big problem for the US and
Pakistan. Now, how much value does
Pakistan have? It looks like the West
has decided to once again ditch
Pakistan. And Pakistan seems to be once
again fishing for a new
daddy, for a new master, which is why it
looks like the they they admitted
publicly that they have been doing the
West's dirty work for for three, four
decades, right? Um so the question you
have to ask yourself is what does the
west what does the US gain by
diplomatically pressuring India or or or
or taking the side of Pakistan or
propagate
Pakistan it's only going to if they do
that it's going to hurt India and it's
going to benefit China do you think the
west wants to do anything that benefits
China today that's the question let's
say okay let's say there's a war that
breaks up between India and Pakistan and
the US sells arms to both sides Let's
say Pakistan has no money to to buy
arms. US gives arms to Pakistan. So then
Pakistan and India are able to fight on
a reasonably even ke and the war drags
on and India becomes a very undesirable
market for for manufacturing. So nobody
wants to invest in India. Then all the
manufacturers who are trying to move off
China where will they go? They will they
go to Vietnam? Does Vietnam have the
capacity the large scale massive
capacity to absorb that amount of
manufacturing capability? No. the only
nation that can do it is
India. So the US would be shooting
itself in its own foot by taking the
side of Pakistan in this. Um so you see
from its from the perspective of its own
self-interest the US is is is not in a
position where it will support Pakistan
if there's a war that breaks out with
India between India and
Pakistan. Mr. 88ers says Donald Trump
said that the Kashmir issue that the
Kashmir issue is over 1,500 years old
but we all know that 1500 years ago
Kashmir was an integral part of Barat
and the issue is barely 75 years old due
to the birth of West Pakistan. What why
is he making such a narrative? What's
your take? Look you to understand Donald
Trump has a certain style of speaking.
He likes to look he is not speaking for
the benefit of the international
audience. He's speaking on the for the
for the benefit of his voters for his
domestic audience. Now if you go to the
US and you live among the Americans for
some time and if you're not in
Washington DC Maryland wherever then you
will see that most Americans have no
idea of what the outside world is like.
They have no interest in the outside
world. They don't know what the outside
world is like. They don't know where is
Cyprus. They don't know where is uh
where is Kashmir. They don't know where
is Kystan. They have no idea where is
Papa Newu Guinea. They don't they don't
care where is Papa Newu Guinea or
Kashmir. And they have no idea when when
which conflict started. So Donald Trump
likes to exaggerate things for
hyperbolic effect. So what is he really
trying to say? So what he's really
trying to say is that this is a conflict
that's been going on forever and we are
not responsible for it. We didn't start
it. We are not part of it. Let let the
two sides decide. That's the message
he's trying to send to his audience, to
his public, to his voters. He's telling
his voters, look, this is not an
American issue. This has nothing to do
with us. We should stay out of it.
That's a forever country. That's what
he's trying to say. I don't know if he's
aware of the history of the conflict or
whatever. Maybe he is, maybe he's not.
But he has a certain style of speaking.
You don't have to you you should not
take it at face value. He's trying to
send a deeper message that the US needs
to stay out of this. This is a different
matter. It's a matter u that that the US
should not be involved in. That's what
he's saying. And maybe maybe he's trying
to make a reference to events that
started about 1500 years ago. Perhaps.
Perhaps. Okay. I don't know. Uh and
maybe it's it's it's a good idea for for
Indians to educate the world about the
history of of this entire matter that it
all begins in
1948. It all begins in 1947. It begins
before that with with the uh with
certain Indian politicians agreeing to
the formation of Pakistan
undemocratically without asking without
taking the consent of the people of
India. and giving up Indian territory uh
without consulting India that's
completely undemocratic. Yes. And then
this artificial temporary nation is
formed and then with the aet with with
the involvement of the UK they grab
parts of Jammu and Kashmir illegally and
then Mr. Neu decides to stop the Indian
army from retaking whatever the Pakistan
has taken and that's why we have PK and
that's the birth of the issue. The issue
is not Kashmir the issue is Pakistan.
Pakistan is an illegitimate nation. It
was created undemocratically. It is land
that is stolen from us. It is our
ancestral land that has been stolen from
us and we're going to retake it whenever
it whenever we do. Maybe we will get to
see it. Maybe our descendants will get
to see it. But it's going to return to
us. That's our ancestral land. So that's
the deal. There is no Kashmir issue.
There's a Pakistan issue and the Tik Tok
has started now for Pakistan. The clock
is ticking backwards now. It's a
countdown. The countdown has started. So
Donald Trump is saying this is a matter
that the US needs to stay out of. That's
what that's the message he's trying to
sell to his audience. That's that's
it. Okay. Dins says if India enters a
war with Pakistan, Bangladesh would
likely join sides with Pakistan. Can
India afford to fight a two-front war
again? Is taking P the final solution to
this or not? If Pakistan balconizes, can
we ensure that they do denuclearize too?
Okay, lots of questions. Let's address
the two-front war issue question in this
matter. Uh not all of the questions.
Look, this idea of a two-front war, it's
something that we have discussed many
times and it's something that Indian
defense experts and and the armed forces
brass and all they discuss all the time.
It's something that is very much at the
forefront of our mind. But the two-front
war issue that we discuss is not
Pakistan and Bangladesh. It's Pakistan
and
China. Pakistan and Bangladesh going to
war with India is not a two-front war.
It's a joke. A two-front war is when
Pakistan and China simultaneously go to
war with India. That's the two-front war
scenario that we take very
seriously. Pakistan and Bangladesh
together going to war. War against India
is not something
to course that's a serious matter but
that's not a two friend war that is
there is a Disney
cartoon okay listen if Bangladesh tries
to go to war with India oh my god look
it makes no sense for them to do that if
they do it it'll be the end of that that
temporary nation also because see
Bangladesh too is a temporary nation
it's an artificial nation carved out of
our territory
can and and look I don't think if
Pakistan goes to war with India
Bangladesh is likely to join they will
be obliterated and flattened and and
sent back into the Bay of Bengal if they
do that they they they stand no chance
absolutely no chance it'll be a great
thing for India if Bangladesh decides to
go to war with India because we get the
chance to cut two chickens necks we get
to uh widen the siliguri corridor
significantly by by at least 100
kilometers and we get to retake
Chhattagam, Chitagong etc. and connect
our far east with the way of Bengal. So
it's great if the Bangladesh want to do
that please please be be my guest please
be be your guests please go
ahead. Stephen says don't you think that
uh Mr. Modi has said Mr. Bhin in the
past recently that it's not the time of
war. It's not the decade of war. So he
will not take any
steps in the any warlike steps in the in
in response to this pahalgam attack
otherwise that statement will look like
hypocrisy.
Okay, look, let's say that it is let's
say that we do all the calculations, you
know, the costbenefit analysis on all
that and we decide that it makes sense
to go to war with Pakistan uh in in the
aftermath of this massacre that they
perpetrated on our
citizens. So, do you think that if it is
the right thing for the nation then the
prime minister should worry about his
own self-image that I will look like a
hypocrite? What is important? What
is what is the duty of the prime
minister or or the leader of a nation to
serve the nation's
interest and it doesn't matter what he
what it makes him look like whether if
it looks makes him look like a liar or a
hypocrite doesn't matter the nation's
interest is
paramount so even if he has said to Mr.
Putin that this is not the time for war
and if he decides that now is the time
for war with Pakistan he can very
clearly say that we desire peace but you
have left us with no option by by doing
this Pakistan has a track record if you
look at the statistics if you look at
the data if you have been tracking the
patterns okay Pakistan has a pattern of
one major terrorist attack against India
every 18 or so months since 2015
2016. So they have been doing this
regularly. So Mr. Modi can say look this
is not the time for war. We desire peace
but you are forcing this on us. You keep
on unleashing terror attacks on us and
we have to stop this. That's the only
way we will have
peace. You know to to
achieve peace you
have what is it?
Um nonviolence ainsa all that you know.
uh a hinsa permodharma right that
nonviolence is is the greatest uh state
of being and all that. So if you really
desire peace and if you really wish
nonviolence to be the norm then you have
to destroy the violent people don't you?
So understand that it doesn't matter
what has been said. If someone
constantly attacks you going to destroy
them. So if the time is now according to
calculations that I'm not aware of to go
to war with Pakistan then it doesn't
matter what Mr. Modi said to Mr. Put
them we were attacked. We didn't start
this but we're going to end it. We can
say that. So we can say that listen it's
not the time for war but we have been
left with no no choice. They started
this so we will end it. So it doesn't
matter if it looks like hypocrisy. And
look if if you start acting
hypocritically as a nation in
geopolitics it means your time is
finally coming. Only the powerful get to
act like hypocrites. Look at the west
the biggest hypocrites of all. And are
they ashamed of being hypocrites? No,
they wear it on the sleeve. So I think
it's time for India to embrace a little
bit of hypocrisy. Okay, that's that
that's when you know that the nation is
finally uh arriving on the global
geopolitical
stage. Pray Paul. Okay, lots of
questions from Pray. You've often
emphasized that India needs 20 years of
uninterrupted growth without getting
dragged into major conflicts in light of
escalating provocations. How should
India strategically balance its economic
aspirations with national security? And
if a limited war with Pakistan becomes
unavoidable, should our doctrine aim to
end it decisively within minutes without
escalating to nuclear options? Okay,
that's good questions. Yes, I have said
this. I have emphasized this multiple
times. I I say I make it a point to say
this over and over again. India needs at
least 20 years of uninterrupted growth
without getting dragged embroiled in any
major conflict. Look, why do I say this?
Today is 2025. This is this is the year
2025. Let's say we're talking about 20
years. 2045 is the time horizon we're
talking
about. Today,
India's per capita GDP is
$2,500 roughly. roughly
$2,500. For us to be
um reasonably welloff
nation, we will need a per capita GDP
which is reaching the $10,000 mark.
Okay, that's when your people can live a
comfortable life. So we want a per
capita GDP of 10,000. We have currently
per capita GDP of
2.5,000 1/4. We need to make it four
times what it is today. That will
require us to have about
7% plus growth compounded growth every
year. 7 plus% okay minimum 7% ideally
more than that. And we'll also need
about 2% of our GDP to be invested
through FDI etc every year and so on. So
it's going to need a multiplicity of
factors for us to reach uh to to start
touching the $10,000 mark in the next 20
years. We need that. So let's say that's
our
target. For that you need a very
peaceful conducive environment in the
country so that you know foreign
investors like to come there and you
come here and the environment is good
and there's no war and there's no
terrorism. So you you need that. So we
don't want to be embroiled in any major
conflict. But let's say someone forces
the conflict on us like Pakistan keeps
doing. In that case what do we do? Let's
say a limited war with Pakistan becomes
unavoidable like Prana is saying what
should we do? How should we approach
that war? Let me tell you what that war
should be like. First of all, it should
be a subnuclear war. The you know should
not trip any nuclear red lines. So how
do you do that? And secondly, how long
should the war last? And what should be
the
objectives? It should be what I would
call a pulse pause war. Pulse pause. It
should be a war in which to inflict a
military and political defeat on
Pakistan in 72 72 hours maximum.
So it's not a blitzkrieg kind of uh
strategy that you use. Blitzkrieg means
you deep penetrate deep into someone's
territory. No, this is going to be a
shallow advance. So maybe 30 40 maximum
50 km you advance and you grab the
territory and then you unilaterally
announce a pause to
hostilities. So you your armed forces
need to be ready for it. Obviously you
know your tank divisions and whatever
you know you need to take substantial
territory not too much shallow advances
30 40 50 km maximum hold onto the
territory and then announce a pause
unilaterally and you need to degrade
their air air their air capabilities air
force and all that means you can crater
their runways take out a few planes
don't attack any of the major
infrastructure don't destroy their
military high command or something don't
don't attack you know the critical
installations and keep it below the
nuclear red lines but in inflict a
devastating u you know blow that is a
clear and and and unmistakable defeat
for Pakistan politically and militarily
and then unilaterally announce a stop a
pause that's a pulse pause so the war
should be over in 72 hours maximum
that's what needs to happen and it
should not be a little little surgical
strike or a one you know one air strike
in the middle of the night no it should
be visible ible it should be
unmistakable that India has inflicted a
disastrous defeat without breaching the
nuclear red lines and don't think that
Pakistan is a crazy and then start
they'll start lobbing nuclear weapons
they want to stay
alive their generals are still in
Pakistan right it's not like they're
operating out of London or or or or
Dubai they are in
Pakistan so they don't want to lose
their lives and the family's lives and
all that so uh the point is it's
definitely possible to have a war,
quick, short, sharp war with a
significant uh visible victory and have
it end in 72 hours. And you know this is
no longer 2019. In 2019 when we did the
Balakur air strike, we did not have the
Rafal. You know technology really
matters. Uh we had those MiGes and all
and we have you know the Pakistanis had
F-16s. Today, India's 26 Rafals can take
out a 100 F-16s from standoff distances
without the the F-16s even coming close
to being dangerous to the Rafals. That's
the kind of capability the Rafal have.
They can take out a 100 F-16s from a
very long distance and the F-16s don't
even have the range to to engage the
Rafals. That's the u that's what you get
when you have a 4.5 generation fighter
plane.
So yeah, the advantage is with us right
now and it is for our leadership to
decide if now is the time for a war with
Pakistan or whether we just want to
strangulate them slowly drop by drop by
various means. Um but if war becomes
unavoidable it should be a very rapid
decisive victory 72 hours maximum pulse
and pause.
Techwise says is this the right time to
use the opportunity to dismantle
Pakistan in front of the west as
prominent leaders have said that they
will support India no matter what
actions we take. Uh they have not said
that they will support India no matter
what actions we take. They have said
that they stand with India and they
support India and all that. India is the
victim of a major terrorist strike. Our
citizens have been massacred 26 of us
and every civilized country has
uh expressed its support towards India.
They they have not said that they will
support India no matter what happens.
Maybe some of the indications could be
could be in that direction but you can't
take it for granted. So then the
question arises is this the time to
dismantle Pakistan?
The shest way to dismantle Pakistan is
to look
uh look you know the temptation
obviously
rises that we want to turn Pakistan into
another Gaza. Every Indian I mean we
have absorbed so many terror strikes. We
have been bled slice by slice, cut by
cut for decades by the Pakistanis. Every
Indian yearns for
revenge and I'm sure for most Indians
nothing will please them more than to
turn Pakistan into another Gaza and then
invite Donald Trump to build hotels
there. Yeah, I'm I'm pretty sure most
Indians would feel that way.
Most maybe 75% 70% Indians will feel
that way perhaps. I'm just guessing a
random number. Uh
so but we have to look at the bigger
picture. What is it that we truly need
as a nation? We need a win. Sure. And we
would love to have some revenge for
everything that's been done to us. But
what's bigger for
us? You know, bigger than revenge is
victory. Sometimes victory itself is
revenge. But we need to
win. Simply getting revenge is not
enough for us. We have to win. What?
What is winning? Winning means Pakistan
no longer exists. And if we can achieve
that without without sending a single
missile, isn't that
better? The biggest, you know, the you
know, yeah, I know that it's Unsunzu who
said this, the best victory is a victory
in which no one even knows that there
was a fight or there was a
struggle. The best general is is that
general who secures victory without
anyone ever knowing that there was a war
somewhere. So I think that's the best
way to win.
Instead of going to war there are so
many other levers that we have the
industry now we can starve them of water
slowly squeeze them gradually drop by
drop every year the pressure will
increase every year the pressure will
increase 26 a new dam becomes
operational 28 another dam becomes
operational we already have many run of
the river dams by 20 mid by by the early
2030s larger dams will become
operational we already building these
projects every year the pressure will
mount on
Pakistan okay And if the pressure
mounts, if the water starts drying out,
if the water flow starts drying out,
that agriculture suffers, that people
will start rising up against the army
that this is because the of the actions
of the army and the ISA are that we are
in this this position. It's not India's
fault. We have to make sure that they
understand this. Then maybe there will
be an internal revolution in Pakistan.
We and you know Pakistan is a nation
that is artificially held together by
the army. The Balois don't want to be
part of Pakistan. The people of Kyber
Pakun who don't want to be part of
Pakistan. The people of Sinduh don't
want to be part of part part of
Pakistan. There are so many people who
don't want to be part of Pakistan. Give
them the opportunity to get out of
Pakistan and become independent. So I
think the process starts now. This is
the right way to do it. Yeah, of course
if if the need is there to to uh launch
a few strikes in Pakistan or whatever,
if if it's important that we do this, if
the calculations fit, then we should do
it. But dismantling will take a little
bit more time in my opinion. Uh, and I
hope I'm wrong. Okay, I hope I'm wrong.
I hope it happens
faster. Praar Gupta says, "Please don't
ignore this question. I've been asking
from February. There was a news article
in February that the terrorist that
terrorist organizations like JM uh,
Lashkar, L etc have invited many Hamas
leaders in some anti-India event
organized in Pakistan occupied Kashmir.
There were also reports of some big game
was being discussed between these groups
and now a brutal terror attack unfolded
in Kashmir and L back to TRF took the
responsibility. Do you see any
connection in these events? Were those
reports warning signs for us which our
intelligence agencies ignored? Were
these attacks ISIS and Hamas backed? Uh
look, I have no
idea whether the Hamas and ISIS were
behind this.
How can I know if I don't have access to
the intelligence reports and and to what
actually happened? And I'm not supposed
to have any access to those intelligence
reports. Obviously not, right? So I
don't know. But look, if Hamas and ISIS
and all were invited, then there could
be linkages. So there is circumstantial
evidence that there are connections for
sure. So all terror groups, they are
both of the same feather. Not all terror
groups but these terror groups Hamas and
uh what ISIS and JM le ISI Pakistan army
they're all birds of the same feather
and they'll flock together then there
must be some kind of connections
possibly between them I can only
speculate I can't say for sure if that
is the case so a terror attack happened
in Kashmir and TRF took responsibility
um yeah so I can only speculate is my
question is my answer there is
definitely the possibility there is a
connection but uh I don't have the
information that could you know that
could prove it or disprove
it okay this
question so this question is asked I get
this question every day on the in the
comments every single day the past 3
years or whatever every day I get this
question is this the right time to take
P back will the US support this move
know that knowing that China might
attack on the other side. Will India do
something like this? How far will India
possibly go to take revenge?
Revenge revenge. Is there a possibility
for India to reclaim PK now? Says uh Ain
Nandan Singh. Abinand Singh. Is there a
possibility for India to reclaim P now
especially after the Bahalgam attack? If
India does reclaim it, will Pakistan try
and threaten nukes? Uh Moak Mandal says,
"Is this not the golden opportunity for
taking back P after the PAL gamma attack
and is India sufficient to block the
indust?" I already discussed that. Okay.
Is this the time to take P back
now? Uh probably not. Let it come, let
it fall into our lap on its own. That's
what I would say. Uh there definitely is
great amount of anger in India. There's
a great desire and thirst for revenge
right now and for Pakistan to be taught
a lesson. So maybe the government may or
may not decide to to take some military
action. If we take it, we will take it
in a calibrated manner. I don't think
we'll take back P. Maybe some part some
portion of P may may be taken back
perhaps. Possibly in the next few days
possibly who knows it's possible.
Uh but I think P all of it may not be
the time perhaps now. Uh will the US
support this move? The US will try and
stay neutral and say that you know
please don't fight and all that. uh but
if they have decided to throw Pakistan
under the bus, they'll be okay with it
perhaps. So it depends on so many on a
variety of parameters that are not quite
clear to us. They're not available. The
the values of the parameters are not not
clear in the public domain. If you are
high up in the government in the defense
ministry or maybe in the RN RNAW or in
the PMO, then you will know what the
exact value of each parameter is and
then you will know whether we going to
be taking this action or that action.
But sitting here I can only say that you
know this is likely or that's likely. So
I think there are multiple scenarios.
Scenario one is that we simply apply the
leverage of the industry and raise on
economic actions etc on Pakistan to
squeeze Pakistan and we diplomatically
isolate them. They no longer have the
backing of the US. They have openly
claimed that the US and the UK and the
west have been paying them for dirty
work. So now they are no longer on good
terms with the
west. So they their only backers will be
what? Pakistan will be China now. Right?
So we can diplomatically isolate
Pakistan. We can make it really hard for
Pakistan to get you know loans from the
IMF and World Bank. We can squeeze them
in the FATF. We can squeeze them in so
many different different ways. Only only
China will will come to help them now.
Right? So it looks like there's there is
a clear bifurcation of the world order
right here. India is going on one side
and Pakistan and China are going another
side. So now I'll not bring in the
Russia factor in this at this bar at
this point in time. So my point is we
have lots of leverage over
Pakistan. Let's
just or maybe if it if it if the
situation is like China may get get
involved in Pakistan soon then maybe it
makes sense to to take some military
action now. So lots of things need to be
considered. I think it is the scenario
one is that we don't take any action. we
apply all kinds of other leverage in
Pakistan that is a more likely scenario
maybe 70% likelihood maybe uh 15%
likelihood is a short sharp war okay and
maybe 15% likelihood is we take back
P that's the kind of probability that I
see okay this is by
Harshawan after Prime Minister Modi met
President Trump in
February several major events occurred
in India. First of all, president's rule
was imposed in Manipur and the situation
is now under control. You think it's
under control? Kind of there are it's
not quite under control. Manipur is
still occupied by foreigners. More than
half of Manipur is is under foreign
occupation. It's not under control.
Yeah, right now there's no major
violence happening. That's the only
thing. But uh the foreigners are still
squatting on Indian territory in
Manipur. Okay. So project K cookie land
for Christ is still it's still go
ongoing. Okay. President's rule was
imposed in Manipur. Secondly, there have
been frequent visits by US government
officials to India. Okay. The Indian
government has agreed to give greater
access to American products. Well, when
Trump goes ballastic and nuclear with
the tariffs, you got to give them
access. Uh next, the the US Treasury
Secretary announced that India is the
first country to sign a trade agreement
with the US. That's going to happen most
likely soon. Soon. It's it's ongoing
right now. Uh negotiations, talks. Uh
six, the Indian government imposed
tariffs on Chinese steel. Well, they
were dumping cheap steel on us. So, we
had to impose tariffs. Yeah, sure. The
seventh, the US government has expressed
support for India's actions against
Pakistan and terrorists. Well, they had
to because they want India on their
side. Next, there are also rumors that
is in that America and Israel supplied
precision strike bombs after the
Bahalgam attack. Okay, I don't discuss
rumors. I have no idea. So my assessment
says hushwartan the Indian government
has agreed to President Trump's demands
while securing India's sovereignty and
gaining greater access to the US market.
What are my
views? Uh my views is that India is
playing is is doing the tightroppe walk
act and India is doing the right thing.
Look, when you have a nation like the
US, the most powerful entity that exists
in the world today, the most powerful
nation ever, you you've got to, you
know, you've got to give them the right
amount of respect and you've got to do
what is right. What is right for
yourself means that sometimes you have
to make concessions to the US and you
have to give them what they want. So if
they don't if they want if they say that
you are imposing too many tariffs on US
goods then we're going to have to give
you cut the tariffs down and give them
more access to our market. But we can do
that in a way that gives us also more
access to their market. So that's why we
have a round of talks that's
happening. So it's going to be hopefully
a win-win. Okay. You want Indian tariffs
to go down? Sure. What can you do for
us? We will bring them down. What will
you do do for us? So that's that's a
win-win kind of situation. Uh so look I
have said this right that during
President Trump's uh presidency India US
relations will be at their highest peak
most likely. I think that's that's
pretty much on its way. Uh does it mean
that India loses some part of its
sovereignty? I don't think India quite
loses too much sovereignty. Uh there's
some give and take obviously in in terms
of you know access to the markets and
all those things.
uh the US will want India on its side in
certain things like when it comes to
actions against China and so on which
means that the India China sector the
frontier the border the LAC may again
turn hot it's a possibility it's a
possibility we have to be careful about
that it means that China and Pakistan
once again become a deal an
item that's also a possibility that's
that's more of a likelihood now looks
like that's that's all happening in real
time right now uh so a lot of things are
happening I told I've been saying this
for for quite some time. This is going
to be a tremendously
uh active geopolitical season. Things
that the kind of geopolitical change
you're seeing in a week today is
typically something that happens in a
decade historically. So a complete
realignment of the global world world
order. I think that u look there's
always a danger a fear that we may end
up becoming a US. I don't think that's
quite the case. Um India is still mostly
a sovereign nation. Manipur raises some
question marks because we still have
foreigners mill I don't know how many
lakhs of them sitting on Manipur
territory Indian territory that's a
problem um so we're going to have to
deal with these things one by one but
uh the Manipur is a geopolitical issue
the Biden administration started this
hopefully the Trump administration ends
that
uh so we'll have to see so I think you
know India US relations uh relations are
on a great trajectory
uh Mr. Modi is is a very good leader, a
very capable leader and uh he is the
right person to deal with someone like
Mr. Trump. They understand each other
very well and I think Mr. Modi will be
able to successfully safeguard our
interests. That that's what I would say
and one certainly hopes that is the
case. Okay, this question any motion
clips says please take this question
I've been asking for the last month.
It'll be weird to tell but I have a gut
feeling that the world is heading
towards World War II. I think let's
think a hypothetical situation. World
War II is going India is battling with
Pakistan, China, India internal civil
war bursts out. What can a person do in
this time? Let's imagine discuss etc. Uh
if you feel okay you want to add viruses
in the mix. Uh my childhood my gut
feeling has never been wrong even for
covid. I started using mask sanitizer 6
months before. Well, well, well. You
have a six sense. My whole family was
COVID positive. I was the only one not
infected. You know, I still don't know
if I ever got COVID or
not. So many you lockdowns and what the
micron micron variant and whatnot. Where
is CO today? Where is COVID today? The
whole world was shut down for that
virus. Where is it today? How come it
doesn't exist anymore? What a joke. It
was boweapon. Anyhow, is the world going
towards World War II? The world is going
towards a cold war and we don't want a
World War II. I hope your gut feeling is
wrong. I don't see it going towards
World War
II. World War II means nuclear war
between the major powers and that's the
that's the end of the world. Um what we
witnessing is a is is a new cold war. So
the entire world is being split into two
camps. I don't think there's a third
camp to be seen very much. Is there a
global south camp? I don't think so. Um
the two camps are the US and the western
le camp and the China and Russia camp in
India I think has probably made a choice
somewhere. I had said this I don't know
how many episodes ago or 20 30 maybe 20
episodes ago or roughly that once Trump
comes to power he's going to ask India
to make a choice. You're either with us
or you're against us. I think India has
made the choice which is why I'm telling
you that something has changed somewhere
in the world. I can sense it. There is
no evidence whatsoever of anything
having changed but I can it's it's a gut
feel like I'm saying something has
changed. I think India and the US are on
the same side now. Uh I don't know what
it means for India
Russia. Probably there will be some kind
of allowance for India Russia as well.
uh because Russia because Russia and the
US have al also have their own
allowance. It's a very complicated
situation but overall the world is
bifurcating. It's splitting into two
camps. It's a cold war situation all all
over again. Supply chains are
fragmenting. Everything is fragmenting
and it's a bifurcation of the gold
global world order and it's this is
called a cold war. So we're going to
have two parallel systems, two parallel
economic blocks and two parallel
geopolitical blocks. and India seems to
be on the western side now. So that's
where we are going. I certainly hope
that there is no World War II situation.
That's that's the end of the world. We
don't want
that. Okay. Questions about scramjets.
Anonymous scientist says DRDO has
successfully completed 1,000 plus
seconds ground test of an active cooled
scramjet combustion engine which is a
gigantic achievement. No other countries
achieved this. What do you think about
this? Pray says uh D was just
successfully tested an active cooled
scramjet engine for 1,3 seconds if I
remember correctly. A breakthrough being
hailed as a major step towards
operational hypersonic cruise missiles.
How significant is this achievement for
India's strategic deterrence and
technological edge? What does this
breakthrough mean for India's position
in the global military technology race?
Especially considering claims that even
that even the US and China have not
achieved yet this level of sustained
scramjet performance. Ashish says DRDO
tested 1000 scramjet engine. Sir Khan of
Russia has a 120 second scramjet phase.
What are the implications?
Okay, pretty interesting stuff happening
in the world and this time we're talking
about India. So, DRDO has something
called the DRDL. It's a laboratory in I
think it's in Hyderabad. Okay. So, this
lab they ran an actively cooled subscale
combuster, a subscale engine for 1,3
seconds. And the air flow was Mach 5
Mach 6 which is five or six times the
speed of sound. Okay. And I think this
was tested in Hyderabad. So until now
the US uh their longest publicly
acknowledged hypersonic run was about
u five five six minutes. I think about
300 something seconds. Okay. Uh DARPA.
Yeah. DARPA does this does this stuff.
And China has claimed that it has done
ground tests about 600 seconds or
something 400 to 600 seconds. But uh
that's a claim that they've made. Nobody
has verified that. Obviously even the US
claim is also a claim. We nobody has
seen that and so on. And um it is
estimated that the zircon the zirkcon uh
scramjet engine
has has it could it could go up to 300
seconds or 400 seconds most likely. So
what India has achieved by crossing the
1,000 second milestone is that see first
of all we are using something called
regenerative cooling. So you know this
this engine the scramjet engine it uses
some kind of fuel. It's going to be a
hydrocarbon based fuel like petrol
kerosene or some kind of exotic
hydrocarbon compound or something. So
when you use regenerative cooling it
means that the fuel itself absorbs the
heat before injection. So it is not just
a fuel it is also a coolant. Can you
imagine that it is not merely a a fuel
which will burn. It is also a
coolant. I remember
um I remember reading as a kid the the
Americans have this aircraft called the
SR71 Blackbird. It's retired now, but it
had an exotic
fuel. The SR71 uh Blackbird. It used a
fuel that would burn only at incredibly
high temperatures. You you you ignite a
matchick and you dump it in the fuel, it
will not burn.
Huh. But it'll burn at extremely high
temperatures. So I think India is using
something like that that that sort of
fuel for the regenerative cooling. It
absorbs heat. It acts as a coolant and
it is also the fuel in the combustion
chamber. Right? And most likely India is
using some kind of alloy or ceramic
material inside the combustion engine,
the liner that can survive about, I
don't know, 1,800 or 2,000° C
temperatures, huge temperatures.
And you will also need some kind of
real-time combustion control algorithms
to keep the fllaying the flame anchored
in pointing in the right direction
despite pressure oscillations and
whatnot at this incredibly high uh mark
number five or six. So it's an
incredible achievement. 1,00 seconds
plus means that now we we have an engine
that can be hypersonic for 1500 km.
The tiron is hypersonic in the end
stage, the last 300 seconds or 120
seconds, whatever it
is. We have an engine that when taken to
the larger scale, when made into a full
scale thing, it can propel a cruise
missile completely completely
hypersonically for 1500 or so kilometers
from launch to impact. It's consistently
hypersonic. It's not supersonic and then
then in the last phase it is hypersonic.
It's hypersonic throughout. That's
incredible.
Okay. So that's fantastic. Now we have
to understand one thing. Important thing
is that the Ciron flies. The Ciron
missile
flies. Okay. What we have is a subscale
test in the ground ground test. Now
we're going to be testing this. We have
a hypersonic uh demonstrator test that
is scheduled for next year 2026 in which
we will most likely test this uh this uh
engine this combuster probably a full
scale version. So right now we have a
scaled down version of that. Let's say
the combuster is supposed to be
hypothetically let's say 1 m long. Maybe
we have something that is about uh 30 cm
or 40 cm long. So it's a small scale
model of the thing. So we have solved
the physics problem. Now we able to
solve the engineering problem.
Understand? So I think it's amazing.
It's awesome. It means that India is
developing technology that very few
nations have and probably a first in its
class technology. I don't think so. It's
possible the Americans may have secretly
tested a 10,00 second engine or
something but well nobody has publicly
announced it. So so I would say great
job DRDO. DRDO gets a lot of flak for a
lot of things but outstanding job and
let's test this on on the on the
demonstrator vehicle next year and
hopefully by the end of this decade we
can have actual hypersonic missiles that
can fly 1500 km fully hypersonic based
on this technology. So I think India is
now so India has transitioned
leapfrogged essentially overnight from a
non-contender in the hypersonic race to
a frontr runner in the hypersonic
race. Overnight we have gone from a
non-contender to a frontr runner in the
hypersonic race. Amazing achievement and
I would like to congratulate and thank
the scientists and engineers for their
work. Tja Ready says, "In an era of
delobalization and supply chain
securityization, should India align with
western technoindustrial coalitions like
the chips act and IPF even at the cost
of alienating the global south where it
seeks leadership. The global south needs
leadership. The global south seeks
leadership should India align with the
chips act and the uh India Pacific,
Indoacific, whatever it is etc. which is
led by the west. I say India should
participate in these things on India's
terms. If you want to be a
leader, you have to set the agenda, not
withdraw from participation. Do you
understand? If you withdraw from
participation, there goes your chance at
leadership. It's over. You can't be a
leader if you don't participate. You
have to not merely participate but you
have to participate in setting the
agenda. So India
should participate in all these
initiatives, coalitions, whatever you
want to call call them. And India should
represent the global south in these and
like we did in the G20, we set the
agenda in the 2023 session, the year
cycle of G20, we set much of the
agenda, right? So India has demonstrated
that we have the diplomatic heft and and
depth to set agendas at the at the
highest level. So India should certainly
participate in the chips act and IPF and
whatever other opportunities we get and
participate in a meaningful way,
participate in a way that aligns with
our interests, contribute something
positive to the world to the world and
puts us in a position when where we
are where we are setting the agenda in
cooperation with others. You don't have
to be the only one setting the agenda.
Obviously not. bigger powers than you
but you should participate in the agenda
setting process. So I think India should
do that for sure. That's how you
uh genuinely become a leader not by
withdrawing and and being
aloof. Okay, let's take some uh
non-geeopolitics questions. Nutan Roshan
says how did how was Mustafa Kimal
Ataturk able to become such a great
leader? How was he able to develop a
nation with radical mentality into a
modern nation from a military n officer
to a great leader? How did he get that
power and how is a leader truly capable
of bringing out the full potential of
his people and lead them towards
development? Okay, look at I can give
you a tour lecture. I can give you a
oneweek seminar also. He's I mean he's
one of a kind. Okay, he was one of a
kind. Um to compress that long story and
make it short, what can I say? How can I
how can I approach that? See, Ataturk
was born in Salonica, Taloniki in in
present day Greece. It was then called
Salonica. It was part of the Ottoman
Empire. And he was born to a Turkish
father in an Albanian origin
mother. Father's name, I forget, Ali
perhaps. Mother's name was Zubeda. Yeah.
Okay. And so on. And he his father died
or something. And his mother remarried
and he was Mustafa came Mustafa was
called he was very rebellious. He was
sent to an army school and he was sent
to many very many various schools. He
was always expelled but he went to the
army school and there he found his
discipline and all that and he was great
at math and all that all those things
you know artillery calculations and all
stuff was good at that and he
participated in various uh military
conflicts and all and he distinguished
himself eventually he was the man
standing against Winston Churchill in
Galipoli
uh the
dinels and he's the guy who saved Turkey
from from the invasion fleet of Winston
Churchill it was 1950 15 the Galipoli
campaign which was a disaster and a
humiliation for Winston Churchill and
for the west and for the
ANZACS Indians also unfortunately had to
participate in that and so he was hailed
as a national hero which he was and he
participated in other various other uh
theaters of war as well eventually uh so
he he was a distinguished general in
1920 20 or wherever it was, he uh after
the the defeat of of of the uh German le
coalition in the in the first world war,
Turkey was partitioned and chopped into
pieces and uh and then there was a civil
war in Turkey, the national war for
indep Turkish war for independence on
which Mustafa Alad fought against the
entire western coalition and the Ottoman
Empire and he defeated them all and he
and he drove the Greeks out of Turkey
and there was the burning of
isbna. So long story long story but he
he was able to win. The essence of
leadership is service and the second
thing is non-negotiable is winning. A
leader must win. A leader must deliver.
You cannot be a failure. So he had those
qualities and he was a military leader
and if you are a military leader you
have the might of the armed forces
behind you and all political power flows
out of the barrel of a gun as Mao said.
So he was able to eventually become the
leader of Turkey, the dictator of
Turkey. Um and look, he was not a saint.
Let me tell you that much. You you leave
his you read his life history, you'll
know that he was not a saint. But he was
a great leader. So you don't need to
have the best personal
qualities to be a great leader for your
people. Was
Ashoke a great person, a great human
being? Probably not. But he was one of
our greatest emperors and I thank him
for his service. Similarly, Mustafa
Kimalad was not a great person, was not
a great human being. He had his flaws.
Okay, let's let's put it that way. But
he was great for his country and he had
a great vision for his country. You know
what he used to say? Uh, you know, he
didn't say this, but he despi you know
what's what's strange about this? It
still makes sense. He despised the
average Turkish person for their sloth,
for their lethargy, for their low
standards. But he had an unshakable
belief in the greatness of greatness of
the Turkish nation. You see the
contradiction there? He could not stand
the average Turkish person, but he had
an unshakable belief in the greatness of
his Turkish nation and so on. So that's
the thing about Mr. Fakim at one of the
all-time greats and he the the changes
he he
he forced on his country and the society
were incredible. It was an orthodox
Muslim
nation and he turned them he he during
his lifetime he turned it into a
secular nation a European nation. He
forced them to reject the Arabic script
and to use the Roman script with certain
changes and so on. The changes he
brought into Turkey to Turkish society
were incredible and deep rooting deep
rooted. And I can't imagine how he was
able to do
it. You know, women could no longer wear
the wheel, the
whale, the borca or whatever it's
called, you know, that thing. And the
the public holiday would no longer be on
Friday. It would be on on on Sundays.
And you know he I think he also mandated
that Turkish mosques could no longer say
Allah Akbar. They had to say
Tanrian. And he he purged the Turkish
language of all the Arabic and Persian
loan words by by replacing those words
with Mongolian words because the Turkish
language is similar to the Mongolian
language. They shown you the Huns and
the Turks and the
Mongols same origins. So he replaced all
the Arabic and Persian loan words with
with Mongolian loan words and so on. So
the
guy he had this force of character,
right? So yeah, one man changed the
whole nation. Incredible
guy. Okay. Uh I don't know what this
name is, but let's uh read the question.
I'm from Germany. Can you explain why
there's IQ differences between
ethnicities? For example, 110 to 115 for
Ashkanazi Jews, 105 to 110 for
HanchChinese, 102 to 104 for white or
ethnic Europeans, less than 100 for
brown people, and less than 90 for
blacks. We'll be pleased if you reply.
Look, IQ depends on a lot of factors.
Okay,
first so let's do a thought experiment.
Let's say there's a there are let's say
there are twins born in the democrat
democratic republic of the Congo
disaster zone in Africa. Let's say there
are twin twins born there. Two let's say
two boys twin boys. You take one boy and
and that boy gets lucky and gets to live
in the US in a foster family and the
other kid sadly remains in Congo and
they both grow up. So by by the time
both are 20, so by when when both the
kids reach 20, they're twins, same
genetics, same everything, but one grew
up in the US, one grew up in Congo, then
at the age of 20, let's say you do an IQ
test, I promise you they're going to
show a significant difference in their
IQs. Okay? So IQ depends on lot of
factors. Even if you have the same
genetics, if you if if the upbringing is
significantly different, you're going to
have a huge difference in IQ. Your
nutrition matters. The kind of nutrition
you got and the kind of nutrition your
brain got, that affects IQ. The kind of
nurture you got as a kid, as a as during
your growing up phase, nature, nurture,
that sort of thing, that
matters. Uh but yes, I'm sure there is a
race component as well. I'm sure there
is. Right. Um so and and there are there
are people very intelligent people who
say that IQ is what a pseudoscientific
swindle. I think Nasam Nicholas Talb one
of one of a very a very intelligent
person he says that uh look IQ
tests it's they are designed in a
certain way. You I've taken an IQ test
only once in my life. That was more than
I don't know what more than 20 years
ago. And I'm pretty sure that if I take
the test again today, I'll have a
different score. So a lot of things
matter. Let's say let's do another
experiment. We we have twins once again.
Okay. Two twins who are born let's say
in Ireland and one twin gets to live in
the US. One stays in Ireland. One
becomes an athlete or tries to be an
athlete. The other becomes a sedentary
drunken person. Well, I can assure you
that if you take an IQ test of the two
twins, the person who is abusing alcohol
will have a much lower IQ. the same
applies to drugs and whatnot. So, a lot
of factors um affect IQ. Is there really
um a race thing in it? I'm I'm sure
there must be some kind of genetic
factor in this.
Um so my question is when these people
take these IQ tests and and they
determine that this race has this range
of IQ, where do do they do it? You know
most IQ tests are in English and if you
are from another country half the time
you may not understand it very well if
English is not your first language. Do
they have IQ test in Swahili? Do they
have IQ tests in Bantau? Do they have IQ
tests in various other African
languages? I'm not sure they do. So
there's that factor also that may
contribute to a lower IQ test. Uh and
you know if you are not mathematically
inclined you may not do well in IQ
tests. in in IQ test you have to
recognize patterns and there is a
mathematical component a logical
component to it and so on so I don't
think IQ is the best measure of a
person's ability and intelligence first
of all uh so that can explain why there
are differences so people who have gone
through a certain kind of education the
western education system they'll find it
much easier to take an IQ test they'll
find the questions more familiar than
someone from Africa who has never been
in a school or someone from Africa
Africa who speaks a certain African
language was forced to study in a French
medium school and then is to take a IQ
test in
English. So you have to understand that
there are lots of factors that go into
the results of the IQ tests that can
make these that can really skew the
scores. And there's also a genetic angle
to the amount of intelligence a person
has. If you take two people any two
people there's going to be difference in
their intelligence level.
Some people are just born more
intelligent. Some people are just
born less intelligent. Is there an
ethnic thing in it? There could be.
Look, I don't know for sure. It's it's
possible. But you know, yeah, it is said
that black black people have low IQ and
brown people also have some supposedly
low IQ. Look at the countries where the
black people live today. Okay. When like
you saying, blacks less than 94 blacks.
These countries are wartorrn. They're
impoverished. They've got abysmal living
standards because of the because of what
happened in the last 150 200 days
colonization, right? They they have
abysmal living standards. Most of the
kids who grow up there are malnourished.
They they don't get a proper
education. And when you grow up in that
environment, you're not going to have
the best performance in IQ tests.
Um, so I think there's a I think there's
a lot of factors like these that that
skew the results of IQ tests and make it
look like some ethnicities, some some
some uh some what do we say? Yeah. Some
some racial groups have higher IQ and
some have lower IQ. Let's take an why
don't we just take IQ tests do an
experiment in which we do the IQ I IQ
testing for people who live in a very
high incarnation only let's say the US
is a good example it's a very
multi-thnic multicultural society uh
mostly white but uh many black people
many brown people Mexicans and Indians
and and Chinese people as well
Ashkanazin Jews there why don't you do
an experiment in which you do IQ tests
across let's say you take
10 let's say you take 10 people from
each ethnic group Ashkan 10 10 ashkan as
a Jews 10 Africanamean people 10 native
American origin people 10
Indian-Americans Indian as in Indian dot
not feather 10 Chinese Americans 10 10
Vietnamese Americans 10 Mexicanameans 10
white Americans and then give them the
same IQ test people who are born and
brought up in the US I think you may see
a very
set of results there. So it has you know
I am pretty sure these the these IQ
tests were not done under uniform
circumstances and yet I am pretty sure
there is some kind of genetic component
that affects the results of IQ tests. So
yeah that that may be a controversial
thing to thing to say but it's possible
that certain ethnicities may be on
average more intelligent than other
ethnicities. It's it's possible. It is
possible. Okay.
Yeah. The feminist hunter says, "How do
you interpret Cleopatra's decision?"
This is old geopolitics. This is ancient
geopolitics 2000 years ago. How do you
interpret Cleopatra's decision to side
with Mark Anthony against Octavian? Was
it a strategic miscalculation or a
desperate move to preserve Egypt's
sovereignty? Look, um, most historians
will say that Cleopatra made a huge
blunder and she was stupid or whatever,
but she was, you know, she had two
options. Uh, become a complete puppet of
the Roman Empire or retain some
autonomy. What Octavian would have was
was
proposing, what Octaven was saying that
you will be the regional governor kind
of thing of of Egypt and your succession
is not guaranteed. your children may or
may not become you know kings of of uh
of Egypt. So Cleopatra had a son
Cesarian. She was a son he was a son of
of Julius Caesar right and and she
wanted her son to be the successor the
next king of Egypt. Octaven would have
given her no such u you know choice as
would not have given uh that concession
to her but Mark Anthony was willing to
give that. So, so you know um Rome was
expanding and Egypt was this fertile
strip of land in the desert in in that
part of uh of the world that part of the
world as you know is a desert region but
you have the Nile and Egypt produced a
lot of grain so the Roman army needed
that that's why Egypt was valuable and
that's why the Egyptian crown was
valuable
uh and Mark Anthony and Octavian were at
loggerheads there was a civil war kind
of situation there used to be a
triumpvirate then they fought
And Mark Anthony was willing to uh give
her the assurance that her son would be
the next king of Egypt. And that would
have given Egypt more sovereignty as
opposed to the deal that Octavian was
giving. Octaven would have turned Egypt
into another Judea. Judea was I mean you
need to read history to understand the
the context but Juda who was a king
Herod I think at the time absolutely
under the boots of the Roman Empire. uh
what Marandani was was proposing what he
was telling her was that he would give
her more prestige more respect and more
a more greater degree of sovereignty
than what Mark than what Octaven who
would later become Augustus would give.
But the thing is that Mark Anthony at
this stage I think his mental balance
was not quite right. He was not making
good choices, good
decisions. A few years ago he was he was
one of the greatest generals of all.
That's why it was so closely associated
with Julius Caesar. Uh but C Caesar gets
assassinated and his adoptive son who is
his grand nephew I think Octavian he
becomes the uh the legal heir of of uh
Julius Caesar and he inherits his legion
the loyalty of his legions and all that
and then eventually you have the civil
war thing and eventually Mark Anthony
dies. he has to commit suicide and
Cleopatra
um she also takes the route of the ASP
ASP
ASP. Uh yeah. So look, she she made a
choice, a strategic choice. It was a
gamble. It was a high-risk choice. The
the and at the time it looked like Mark
Anthony was was winning. But eventually
octave. So you know, you got to make a
choice in life. Some sometimes you win,
sometimes you lose. And sometimes in in
geopolitics when you lose, you lose it
all. So that's what happened with
Cleopatra. Okay, let's take some
questions from the live chat, shall we?
Okay, let let me take for the next few
minutes questions from the live chat.
Um, okay. Dave Rod says, "This is the
niche niche question. Why did Naven
Patnayak meet the pope during his vis
visit to
Italy for WFP in 22? Was there something
some message beyond the
pleasantries?" I have absolutely no
idea. I'm sorry. I I I don't know. Look,
I don't know what people's motivations
are. etc. I I don't know.
Sorry.
Um let us see. Okay. Shri Ramach Andrea
Namaha says, "What about no first use
nuclear policy? Will it be changed?" I
think we can keep it at no first use. It
doesn't mean we will not use it first.
Uh
um we can keep some strategic ambiguity.
I think China has a no first use policy.
we have a no I don't know I maybe we can
revisit that depending on how things
go when it comes to our nuclear nuclear
policy uh the the real concern for us is
not Pakistan the real concern is always
China right so it all depends on the
relationship with China not with
Pakistan some incident with Pakistan
will not make us change our nuclear
policy it's always going to be focused
on on the bigger threat which is China
um make but says if you have to take an
IQ test you're doubting your IQ and
exposes your IQ. Sir, I am a very stupid
low IQ person. That's why I took a low
IQ. That's why I took an IQ test. All
right, sir. What can I say? Maybe you're
curious as to what is my intelligence
level on a certain scale. But it's okay.
You can believe and you can see the
world the way you
like.
Um okay. Um let's see some more
questions. Shri Ramachandra again says
Hinduism is about dismantling a dharma.
That is true. Yes.
Yes. Okay. Now lots of Okay. Let's see
some more
questions. Tanachundra says Pakistan new
sugar daddy in making but India is
permanent daddy. Okay
sir.
Um Chirai says in the worst case
scenario if war were to happen between
India and temporary nation what would be
the red lines for India and for the
temporary relation? For the temporary
nation. For the temporary nation, we're
talking about nuclear red lines here. Uh
for us, you don't use nukes, we'll not
use nukes. That's the deal. For them,
it's it's about an existential thing. So
if they feel that Pakistan will no
longer exist, then they may use nukes.
So as long as we don't take too much
territory, we make shallow
gains and we don't destroy their nuclear
installations and all that or their
draal pindi headquarters or the army the
home of the army general chief of staff
or whatever that that's the red line. So
as long as we don't do that they are
okay.
Um okay Amisha says one of the solutions
to Kashmir is to change the demography
of Kashmir. Settle the Hindu population
there. Give them protection. Kashmir
will change. Do you agree? Look what
have the Chinese done in Tibet? They've
changed the demography of Tibet. The
Tibet native Tibetan people are now a
minority in in Tibet itself. Lassa is
now the capital of Tibet is now a Han
majority
place. Learn from your enemies.
One of the solutions is to change the
demography. It's your country. You can
do whatever you want. You can people can
settle wherever they want. So after the
abrogation of article 370, how many
Hindus have moved into
Kashmir? Hindus have been going to
Kashmir for tourism to give them the
tourism revenues. But how many of the of
the Kashmir pundits have been allowed to
to resettle in Kashmir? Nobody has been
allowed. But Hindus are okay. Ah, very
good. Let's go Kashmir tourism. This is
what happens. So uh I agree with you.
You know what you should do? We should
settle people with a military background
in
Kashmir. There are lots of people who
would love to settle in Kashmir. People
with a military background, young
younger people, not not not people in
the 60s and 70s. Settle them in Kashmir.
Give them arms
licenses and and you know you can do it
that way. There are all kinds of good
creative solid solutions and what Amisha
is proposing is an excellent
solution. Yes, it should happen. Why are
we being nice forever? First of all, why
have the the Kashmiri pundits not been
given the freedom to resettle in
Kashmir? They're still feeling not safe.
No, they're still feeling unsafe. That's
why they're not going back, right? They
can go back only if they feel that their
lives are secure. So, the government is
not able to do that thus far. Now,
things need to change.
So I agree with Amisha and she's making
a very uh valid uh proposal
here. Okay.
Um Priyanka Kumari says, "Why can't we
change the education system fast,
especially history in high school?"
Yeah, I don't know
why. I used to get really frustrated
with this, but now I'm like, "Okay, it's
okay. I would do it. The first thing I
would do was would be to change the
education system. I know it's not easy.
It takes time. You have to do it step by
step. It's called phased deployment.
Phased deployment. You to deploy any
change in phases. It will take you
minimum 20 years to change the education
system. But you have to start at
somewhere. You start at the lowest
level. You start with nursery first
year, then junior kg, then senior kg,
then start at one and take it all the
way for 20 years. change it phase by
phase and you need to have a very clear
idea of what change you're
making. We can do it. It's everything is
possible but maybe it's maybe it's
possible but too difficult. I don't
know.
Um says how can we pause or restrict the
patrol access of Pakistan? Look we don't
control patrol access. Um we control
water access. So we're going to test
that. We're going to we're going to
control
that. Uh Mr. Atiator says, "Recently a
team of European scientists observed
quantum rain phenomenon. Can you please
explain how it's different from normal
rain and what breakthroughs can be
achieved with this? I have no idea. I've
not seen it. I've not seen the piece of
news. Quantum
rain?" I'll have to look it up. I'm not
sure. Okay. I haven't seen the news. If
I were to guess what does it mean? I
don't know. Does it mean that they've
observed raindrops shattering at the
quantum level in some way? Raindrops are
held together by surface tension. That's
why water is usually ra you know
globular in nature when it's falling
when it falls the atmosphere pressure
makes it flatter then it falls and
shatters and there's a whole complex
interplay of various navier stokes
equations and equations that
uh surface tension involvement whatnot
and do you is there are you able to
observe that the quantum level I'm not
quite sure okay so I I I don't know what
it is once I see it then I'll be able to
comment on
that what do Think about Augustus and
his political maneuvers. He was a
genius. That's why he became the first
emperor of the Roman Empire. He said
that I'm going to achieve what they
prevented my great uncle, my grand uncle
from achieving. His grand uncle was
obviously Julius Caesar who adopted
Octavian as his legal heir as his as his
adoptive son. So they were related
related by blood and Caesar adopted him
officially as his adoptive son. That's
why uh Augustus got the political
legitimacy and uh he was he was
obviously great. Augustus Octaven became
Augustus. All right. All right. All
right. What's my height? How does it
matter?
Okay. Okay. Bobby. Bobby. Good to see
Bobby after a long time. uh Mongol takes
back inner East
Turkiststan. Okay. Mongolia takes back
inner Mongolia. East Turkiststan
separates and Tibet becomes independent.
Then there will be peace in that region.
You know, you could you could argue that
there's there is already peace there.
There's no war happening there. There's
no terrorism happening there. There is
peace there. You
know, back in the day, I don't remember
who it was that said this about the
Roman Empire, but someone said that the
Romans, they create a wasteland and then
they call it peace. It's called
pacification. So, you know, it depends
on your on your definition of peace. Uh
you can have peace through strength and
by force and by hgemony. You can impose
peace by hedgemony by by by subjugating
a conquered population. You can do that.
There will be peace in in a technical
sense, but it will be injustice. So we
want peace and justice
together. For that I would say Tibet
well
yeah. Yeah. So I I know what you mean.
Yes. Okay. What next? We'll take one one
or two more questions.
Um, Surendra Gupta says, "Update on next
America, understanding America episode."
Yeah, the next one is edited. It's
ready. It's coming out this Thursday.
And there's another podcast coming out
this Tuesday, so you can look forward to
it this time, and I apologize for the
delay uh in the in the understanding
America series, but it's it's coming
back on track
now. Uh, okay.
Sankalpa says, "Have you watched Chava?"
I haven't seen it. Sorry, I haven't seen
it thus far. No time to watch movies and
things. I would love to. I'd love to
watch two movies a week in a theater,
but no
time. Which branch in physics is easiest
and vice versa. Look, if you know if
you're good at math, every branch of
physics is easy. I mean, that's that's
my worldview. It may be different from
for others. The key to being good at
physics is to being really good at math
because math is the language of physics.
You want to solve any physics problem,
you do you have to be good at math. So
yeah, you got to do all those books. You
have to do differential equations. You
do linear algebra. You got to do
topology in some cases. Then you've got
to do FIA transforms and matrices and
yeah, you've got to do all that. So,
Marry Bose is the way to go or you
can we got some more books here and
there. It's been a while. So, yeah, if
you're good at math, you can do any
branch of physics is easy for me. I'm
always drawn to the difficult parts, the
challenging parts.
So,
okay. Uh Amisha says Indian media is so
insensitive. They are making studios of
war room so bad. Okay. I have no idea. I
don't watch Indian media. This past
week, I was inv I was I was requested
multiple times to appear on those 9:00
p.m. uh shouting
debates. Uh I did not. So yeah, look,
war is a war is hot. War sells, right?
And and in the Indian public, they love
shouting, they love debates, they love
words. Indians are so fond of arguing
and discussing things to the infinite
level.
So that's why you know the TV studios
these these new studios they make war
rooms huge maps on the wall and the
anchor will hold a stick and point at
the map and there will be three four
army generals retired guys who will be
saying war and so on it it's fun if if
you are into entertainment but what's
how does it educate the public I'm not
quite
sure okay Bobby says Canada has an
election coming up what do you think
about each of the candidates I've not
really looked into the candidates I'm
sorry I I
don't Maybe Canada is not that important
for me. It makes no difference for me
who comes to
power. M is there a good candidate out
there because who who is there and uh
Carney Carney some guy called Carney
Tudau is gone. I think they're all much
of more of the same. They're all like
it's like the the the merrygoround in
the UK. One leader comes and another
come, another one goes and then there's
another one after a few months and it
makes no difference whatsoever. None of
them are leaders. They're just
suits. They're simply suits. I think the
same applies to Canada. So I I don't
really know. Maybe I should pay a little
bit of attention. Maybe next next week,
next weekend, I'll I'll do a bit of
homework and check out all these
candidates who they are and maybe I can
give you a better better a better answer
to the to this question.
And with that, I
think
Okay.
Um, does sir like video games? Um, I
don't get to play video games. I I you
know, I once had a PlayStation. I had a
PlayStation 2 when it was brand new, you
know, hot hot thing. I bought it for
like $450 or something. And I used to
play some games. Um, a car crashing game
or
something and so on. I I've played some
video games once in once in a while, but
I don't really get the time to play it.
Um, yeah. So, I'm
not a big user or connoisseur of video
games. Okay, with that we end today's
episode. Thank you so much everybody for
all the questions. I really enjoyed
this. For a change, we've discussed the
temporary nation and yep, thank you so
much for your questions and apologies
those of you whose questions I could not
take. And next weekend we continue this.
So until then take care. Uh please keep
learning, keep asking questions, keep
raising your standards. And I will see
you next weekend. Thank you so much.
Bye-bye.